Kyler R. Jacobs

Portfolio website at: kylerintech.pythonanywhere.com

GitHub: https://github.com/KylerJacobs

Linkedln: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kyler-jacobs-931260276/

Objective

Highly motivated Python developer with a background in leading teams and optimizing systems for enhanced productivity and success, now seeking entry-level opportunities to transition into the dynamic field of machine learning and data science. Leveraging my intermediate Python skills, I aim to apply my leadership experience, problem-solving abilities, and passion for continuous learning to contribute to a company's success in driving innovative data-driven solutions.

Summary

With a background in agriculture, I bring a strong work ethic and deadline-driven personality to any project. My ability to solve problems and communicate with associates makes me a great addition to any company. Although I do not have any professional experience, please visit my portfolio website, or my GitHub account, to see a few of the many skills I have gained in the field of data science and machine learning. I know I can be an asset to any organization that strives for improvement.

SKILLS

Programming Language: Python

Data Manipulation: Jupyter Notebooks, Pandas, NumPy, SciKitLearn

Data Visualization: Matplotlib, Bokeh

Other Skills: HTML, CSS, Strong Communication, Problem-solving, Adaptable,

Punctual

EDUCATION

- Bachelors of Integrated Plant Sciences in Field Crop Management
 - Washington State University
 - Graduated spring 2018
- Zero to Mastery Certificate
 - Complete Python Developer in 2023: Zero to Mastery

EXPERIENCE

SweetWater Farms, LLC. Cheney, WA - Assistant Grow Manager

July 2022 - April 2023

- Worked directly with the head grower to establish everyday function and prepare for future production.
- Maintained organization in the greenhouses and tracking softwares.
- Established new labor protocols for increased productivity and overall plant health.
- Gave instructions to greenhouse crew to ensure productivity and increase efficiency.

Ag Grow, LLC. Pullman, WA - Compliance Manager

December 2018 - July 2022

- \bullet $\,$ Worked with head grower to establish and maintain organization of tracking softwares and physical plants.
- Occasionally led greenhouse crew in daily tasks.
- Worked within the labor systems in place.

Washington State University Winter Wheat breeding Facility. Pullman, WA – Field/Laboratory Assistant

May 2016 - November 2018

- Help maintain clean wheat plots through chemical sprays and manual weed removal.
- Harvest plots and record data
- Run critical tests (falling numbers, protein content, moisture content) that impact global wheat production.